[Road to Success]
[星のように煌めく]
[Episode 11]
[第11話]
Where is he?
あいつは？
It's him.
この人よ
He was following me.
私をつけてきたの
I wasn't following her.
つけてないよ
I was trying to find you.
お前を探しに来たんだ
He's my manager.
私のマネージャーだ
You have a manager?
マネージャーがいるの？
There's nothing weird about
サウサンプトンのコーチが
Nanton's coach having a manager, right?
マネージャーを持っても おかしくないだろ
What's wrong?
どうした？
What's with your outfit?
その服はどうしたんだ？
Can't afford to buy a pair of pants?
ズボンを買う金もないのか
You know nothing about fashion.
分かってないな
See this?
ほら
This is the "missing lower body" look.
「下半身失踪コーデ」だ
It's really in style right now.
今 流行ってんだよ
If you don't button up your coat now,
そのコートをちゃんと着ないと
I'm seriously going to make your lower half disappear.
本気で下半身を失踪させてやるぞ
So out of touch.
ダッサ
Ms. Lin.
林先生
I've heard so much about you.
お噂はかねがね
Let me formally introduce myself.
改めて自己紹介しよう
I am Felix Yu,
余波だ
Winfred's manager.
王法さんのマネージャーである
[Felix Yu, Manager of Yongchuan Hengjiu Youth Football Club]
[余波 永川恒久少年 サッカークラブのマネージャー]
Too bad.
残念ね
I honestly thought you were an exhibitionist,
露出狂かと思って
and I wanted to test how strong your mentality was.
あなたのメンタルの強さを 試そうとしたのよ
You guys carry on.
どうぞお二人で
I'll leave you alone.
お構いなく
I get your fashion.
そのおしゃれ 分かるわ
Seeing is believing.
百聞は一見にしかずだね
She really is an interesting girl.
実に面白い子だ
Did you come here just to mooch off mine?
私のズボンを借りにきたのか
Let me tell you, they wouldn't fit. They're too long for you.
長すぎて似合わないぞ
This is called fashion taste.
これがファッションセンスだ
Fashion taste.
ファッションセンス
What do you know?
分かってるか
Seriously.
まったく
"Fashion."
ファッション
So, still two teaspoons of sugar?
で 砂糖は２杯でいいのか
Giving me coffee at this hour?
こんな時間にコーヒーを
Are you trying to keep me up and torture me all night?
一晩中 苦しめるつもりか
I'll have water.
水でいい
Alright then.
分かった
Water, water, water. Okay.
はいはい 水ね
Here's your water.
水だ
So,
それで
you're certain
本当に
that she's not Spade Q?
彼女がスペードのＱじゃないと
She's not.
違う
Bro, I remember you were a materialist.
お前は唯物論者だったはずだ
When did you become an idealist?
いつから唯心論者に
Do you really think someone
かわいくて
who's cute, a bit scatterbrained, emotional,
そそっかしくて感受性が豊かで
and considerate of others
思いやりのある人が
could be the kind of ruthless person
冷酷に
who sets up traps to lead people to their deaths?
罠を仕掛けて 人を死に追いやると思うか
Would you put training wheels on a bike
賭けの勝ち負けのために
and force yourself to ride it just to win a bet?
補助輪をつけて 無理やり自転車に乗る？
♪ Two souls aligned ♪
♪ 二つの魂が寄り添って ♪
♪ In silent gravity ♪
♪ 静かな引力に導かれ ♪
Would you cheat on a bet
賭けのためにズルをして
by having your students help you meet your exercise targets?
生徒にノルマを達成させる？
♪ Heal my heart ♪
♪ 君のすべてで ♪
Would you plot against your neighbor,
隣人をハメようとして
♪ With every part of you ♪
♪ 私の孤独な心を 癒してくれた ♪
only to end up scaring yourself?
逆に自分が驚かされる？
Would you do something just for laughs,
面白半分で
♪ Our words flow ♪
♪ 言葉はそっと ♪
then end up using your neighbor's washing machine?
隣人の洗濯機を借りる？
♪ A gentle stream ♪
♪ 優しい川のように流れて ♪
Besides,
それに
she was willing to put her own life on the line
彼女は生徒を助けるためなら
to save a student.
自分の命も顧みない
♪ They glow like fireflies ♪
♪ 蛍のあかりが ♪
Do you think Spade Q would ever do that?
スペードのＱがそうすると思うか
♪ Inside a silken dream ♪
♪ 柔らかな夢へと舞い降りる ♪
The last time you talked this much
お前がそんなにしゃべったのは
was when you were making a case for Jason.
ジェイソンの弁護をした時以来だ
♪ We talk the cool night, breeze away ♪
♪ 夜通し語れば 夜風も静かに眠ってゆく ♪
Anyway, when it comes to these details,
とにかく こういう ささいなことの方が
I think they're more convincing than any data could ever be.
どんなデータよりも説得力がある
♪ We trace the roads ♪
♪ この長い道を ♪
Okay, got it.
分かった
♪ That never see an end ♪
♪ どこまでも歩いていこう ♪
So in your mind, the probability of her being Spade Q is...
じゃあ お前の中で彼女の可能性は
♪ We softly calm the hidden doubt ♪
♪ そっと拭ってあげる ♪
Never mind, don't tell me. I'll check for myself.
もういい 言うな 自分で見る
I'm still not used to you talking so much all of a sudden.
急に口数が増えると調子が狂うな
♪ Seen in each other's eyes ♪
♪ その瞳に浮かぶ迷いを ♪
♪ Bring to life ♪
♪ 内なる自分を目覚めさせよう ♪
[The probability of Lin Wanxing being Spade Q: 0%]
[スペードのＱ 林晚星 確率0％]
Okay.
よし
Since she's been cleared of suspicion,
彼女が違うなら
shouldn't you get going?
もう行ったらどうだ？
Where to?
どこへ？
Remember to check your phone later.
後でちゃんと見ろよ
I'll send you information of
お前に興味のあるクラブを
all the clubs that are interested in you,
全部送っておく
especially Hengjiu.
特に恒久だ
I think I get what you mean
なるほどな
by that "especially."
その「特に」か
Alright, I won't keep you in suspense.
分かった もうもったいぶらない
I'm here
俺がここに来たのは
on a mission from my goddess.
女神様の使命を背負ってるからだ
She's offering a very high budget
彼女は高額の予算を出して
and is determined to get you, Mr. Winfred,
ミスターウィンに食い下がってでも
to be the club coach.
彼をクラブのコーチにさせる気だ
I'm just here to lay the groundwork.
俺は先遣隊として来た
So, mission failed.
先遣隊は失敗だ
Seriously?
おいおい
You're really going to be this ruthless to your own buddy?
兄弟にそんな冷たいのかよ
Give me my watch back.
時計を返せ
I don't have it at the moment.
時計は今ない
Besides,
それに
you know perfectly well what kind of person
お前の姉さん 俺の女神様がどんな人か
your sister, my goddess, is.
知らないわけじゃないだろ
Just you wait.
まあ見てろって
I...
俺が
You think I'm afraid of her?
彼女を怖がると思うか
But I am.
俺は怖いぞ
If she has something to say,
何か用があるなら
she can come and tell me herself.
自分で直接言いに来いと伝えろ
Why send a minion over?
使いっぱしりまで寄こして
I'm just here to lay the groundwork.
俺はただの先遣隊だ
I never intended to sway you or anything.
お前をどうこうする気はない
I wonder what that manager
あのマネージャーは
wants with Winfred.
王法に何の用かしら？
Maybe I should go and finalize
コーチの契約
the coaching contract with him as well.
私も彼と話を進めようかな
"The football team will train as usual.
チーム練習は通常どおり
But the indoor theory classes need to be arranged
ただ室内での座学は
as soon as possible."
早めにね
He still wants to have indoor theory classes?
まだ座学をやる気があるなんて
Doesn't sound like someone who's planning to leave.
辞めるようには見えないわね
[Felix Yu, Manager of Yongchuan Hengjiu Youth Football Club]
[余波 永川恒久 少年サッカークラブのマネージャー]
If he really leaves the football team,
もし彼が本当に サッカー部を辞めたら
what will happen?
どうなるかしら？
Guess I'll cross that bridge when I come to it.
その時に考えよう
I think
これは
I'll give this to Lin Lu.
林鹿にあげよう
[Administrative Building]
[管理棟]
Director Qian.
銭主任
Whenever I need him, he's never around.
肝心な時にいないんだから
Dear Director Qian,
拝啓 銭主任
with the exams approaching,
試験が間近に迫り
the team is in urgent need of...
チームには急ぎ...
Would that sound too formal?
堅苦しすぎるかな
[If I can save a heart on the verge of breaking,]
[もし私が 今にも壊れそうな心を救えるなら]
[then I will not have lived this life in vain.]
[私はこの人生を無駄にはしない]
So Qian also reads poems?
銭先生も詩を読むのね
Ms. Lin?
林先生
Director Qian.
銭主任
Are you
私に
looking for me?
何か用か
Yes.
はい
The football team needs an empty classroom
サッカー部の補習で
for tutoring sessions.
空き教室が必要なんです
Have you tried the Academic Affairs Office?
教務課へ行きなさい
I have.
行きました
They said there are no empty classrooms available.
でも空きはないと
So,
ですから
could you please step in and help us out, Director Qian?
銭主任に お願いできませんでしょうか
I'm afraid there's nothing I can do about that.
それは力になれそうにないな
You have to understand, classrooms are reserved ahead of time,
考えてもみろ 教室は予約制だ
and every room is already fully scheduled.
どの教室も授業でいっぱいなんだ
I can't just disrupt
他の先生の
other teachers' classes, right?
授業を邪魔するわけにはいかない
Try to figure something else out.
君が別の方法を考えなさい
Where there's a will, there's a way.
案ずるより産むがやすしだ
Good luck.
頑張れ
That was a really quick rejection.
即答で断られた
"Handsome, kind-hearted, gentle yet powerful,
イケメンで心優しく力強い
the all-mighty Aladdin Qian Lamp:
万能のランプの精 銭様
Please grant us a place for tutoring sessions.
どうか補習の場所をお与えください
Sincerely praying,
心からお祈りします
desperate Lin.
困っている林より
Come on, ladies first.
はい レディーファースト
You go first.
どうぞ
Where did you go?
どこ行ってた？
To buy drinks.
飲み物を買ってきた
Continue.
続けよう
What's this?
何だこれ？
What is this thing?
一体 何だこれ？
Such ugly packaging.
ダサい包装
Hold on.
待って
Don't open it yet.
まだ開けるな
Could this be a bomb Wen Chengye planted
文成業がお前への腹いせに
to get back at you?
仕掛けた爆弾じゃないだろうな
-What are you talking about? -What a waste.
- 何？ - そんな
It's not entirely impossible.
あり得ない話じゃない
Have you ever received
何か似たような
anything weird like this before?
変な物を受け取ったりしてないか
[100 free football equipment rentals]
[サッカー用品無料貸出券 100回分]
A while ago, Qin Ao and the others
この前 秦敖たちも
also received some weird stuff like this.
同じような変な物を受け取ったよな
This...
これ
Could this be another puzzle from the mysterious person?
また「謎の人物」の謎々か
This is too much of a coincidence.
偶然すぎる
Open it and see.
開けてみて
[Destiny]
[運命]
Why is there a question on this?
問題があるぞ
Destiny?
運命？
[Question 1] [Question 2]
[質問1][質問2]
Why are there questions in here?
こっちも問題だ
[Chance]
[チャンス]
Chance? These are also questions.
好機 これも問題だ
[Question 1] [Question 2] [Question 3]
[質問1][質問2][質問3]
[Map of Hongjing]
[宏景市地図]
A map?
地図？
This string of numbers...
この数字は
What does it mean?
どういうことだ？
Write it down first.
メモしておこう
[Question 1] [Question 2] [Question 3]
[質問1][質問2][質問3]
I can't figure them out.
分かんない
What do you have?
みんなが持ってるのは何？
All questions we don't understand.
分からない問題ばかりだ
We don't know what they are either.
何だかさっぱり
They're all math problems.
全部数学の問題だ
So the fun puzzles you were talking about
面白い謎解きって
are just math problems?
数学を解くことかよ
Last time it was a word puzzle.
前回は穴埋めクイズで
They were all four-character idioms.
四字熟語ばっかり
At least I could understand them.
まだ意味は分かったのに
Among you,
この中で
whose math grades are better?
数学ができるのは誰？
I think it's Yu Ming.
俞明が一番だと思う
Yeah, he can score over 80.
ああ 80点以上は取れる
Out of 100?
100点満点
Out of 150.
150点
I'll solve them then.
やっぱり私がやるわ
You should be the one doing it anyway.
そりゃあそうなるべきだよ
After all, you're the genius
150点満点で
who can score 140 out of 150.
140点も取れる秀才なんだから
Show us what you've got, genius.
秀才のお手並み拝見だ
[Determinant of Matrix A]
[行列Ａの行列式]
[In the additive group of residue classes modulo 4, Z4]
[加法群Ｚ４における ４を法とする剰余の加法群]
[What is the order of the element 2?]
要素２の次数は？
The Destiny questions.
「運命」の問題
For Question 4, 5, and 6,
４ ５ ６
the answers I got
計算で導き出した答えは
are 6, 6, and 1 respectively.
６ ６ １よ
If we arrange the answers for Chance and Fate questions
チャンスと運命の計算結果を
separately...
それぞれ並べる
Look.
見て
I get dizzy just looking at numbers now.
数字を見るとめまいがする
Then what's the connection between these numbers?
この数字に関連性はあるのか
The connection between the numbers might not be important.
数字同士の関連性は 重要じゃないかも
What's important is their connection to the map.
重要なのは地図との関連性よ
[Xu] [Qing] [Wen] [Wang]
[徐][清][温][王]
What's the connection?
どんな関連だ？
Why are the questions divided into 2 parts, "Destiny" and "Chance"?
なぜ運命とチャンスに 分かれてるんだ？
And why
それに
[Xu] [Qing] [Wen] [Wang]
[徐][清][温][王]
do both answers to Question 1
問題１の答えは２つとも
contain decimal points?
小数点が付いてる
This is the map of Hongjing.
これは宏景市の地図だ
If there are numbers anywhere...
数字があるとすれば
Exactly. They're coordinates— latitude and longitude.
そうよ 緯度と経度
The patterns in these numbers
この数字の並びは
match the latitude and longitude almost perfectly.
緯度と経度の表示と一致してるわ
29.58? 106.53?
29.58 106.53
[Xu] [Qing] [Wen] [Wang]
[徐][清][温][王]
So the intersection point is...
交差点は
[Luoxin Photography Studio]
[羅新写真館]
A photography studio?
写真館だ
Are we sure we're in the right place?
場所は間違ってないよな？
Don't worry.
安心して
Although math is my weak subject—
数学は苦手だけど
I only got 141 out of 150 on the college entrance exam—
大学入試も141点だったし
I'm pretty sure I got it right.
でも間違いないはず
We haven't used the code
この地図の裏のコード
on the back of this map yet.
ずっと使ってない
Could it be related to this place?
ここと関係があるかもしれないな
Oh, right.
そういえば
Now that you mention it, I suddenly remember.
言われて思い出したわ
Photos from when we were kids
子供の頃の写真の裏には
do usually have codes written on the back.
確かにコードがあった
Fu, you're really smart.
付 さすがね
Let's go in and ask.
じゃあ入って聞いてみよう
-Come again. -Thank you.
- またいらっしゃってください - ありがとうございます
Hello.
こんにちは
Hi, excuse me.
すみません ちょっとお聞きしたいんですが
Is this photo code from your shop?
この写真のコードは こちらのお店のものですか
In this day and age,
今の時代は
we don't register photos with codes anymore.
もうコードで 写真を管理してないんです
Did you use them before?
前はどうですか
I think our former boss used them in the past.
前の店長は使ってたみたいですけど
Miss,
お姉さん
could you please check for us?
調べていただけませんか
But I have urgent matters to handle right now.
でもこっちも急ぎの用があるんです
I'm sorry.
すみません
Maybe you could...
やはり...
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
Let's step outside first.
いったん外に出よう
Excuse me.
すみません
Thanks.
ありがとうございます
It's nothing.
いえいえ
Thank you, Miss.
ありがとうありがとうございます お姉さん
Could it be that we got the answer
今回のゲームの答え
to the game wrong this time?
俺たちが間違えたのか
It can't be.
そんなことない
I think we just haven't found the right answer yet.
まだ正解にたどり着けてないだけよ
[A Snapshot of Time]
[時の垣間]
A vintage photo-shoot event.
レトロ写真イベント
What if we go in for a photo-shoot?
俺たちが入って撮影すれば
Only couples and spouses can participate.
カップルと夫婦限定だ
[Event Rules: Open only to couples and spouses]
[イベントルール 参加資格はカップル 夫婦のみとなります]
[Please make an appointment in advance. Sessions will be arranged by appointment.]
[撮影のご予約は 事前に指定の時間帯でお願いいたします]
Who's going?
誰が行く？
Ms. Lin,
先生
The only person we have here who might be able to take couple photos
この中でカップル写真を 撮れそうなのは
is you.
先生しかいないよ
Ms. Lin, you're the only one who can do it.
先生 撮れるのは先生だけだ
Ms. Lin, you're in your prime.
林先生は若くてお美しい
You might as well take some photos as a keepsake.
記念に写真を撮るいい機会だ
It'll be a win-win.
一石二鳥じゃないか
Think about it, Ms. Lin.
林先生 考えてみて
[Little Savage Tribe]
[野人部落]
It took us an hour to solve the math problems,
数学の問題に１時間もかけたのに
but only 5 minutes to get kicked out.
追い出されるのはたった５分か
So what do we do next?
次はどうする？
Ms. Lin
林先生
needs to find someone to take couple photos with
誰かと一緒に写真を撮って
and sneak into the photo studio,
写真館に潜入し
so as to continue finding clues.
手がかりを探すんだ
How exciting!
ワクワクするな
What kind of spy movie plot is this?
スパイ映画みたいだ
Ms. Lin.
林先生
So have you found someone to take couple photos with?
それで 撮影パートナーは見つかった？
No.
ううん
I was wondering if it's really necessary to go this far.
そこまでする必要あるのかなって
We don't even know if the mysterious person
それに この贈り主が
who sent the gift box is just messing with us.
私たちをからかってる だけかもしれない
Don't you want to know the answer?
謎を解きたくないのか
I do.
解きたい
If it really comes down to it,
どうしても見つからなければ
I might as well just hire someone.
いっそ誰か雇おうかと
It's only an act for the occasion anyway.
どうせ その場限りの芝居だし
Anyone will do.
誰を頼んだって同じでしょ
Ms. Lin.
林先生
My uncle is very easygoing,
俺の叔父さん 話が分かるし
and he has muscles.
筋肉質で
He's very photogenic.
写真写りも抜群なんだ
Ms. Lin.
先生
My cousin's also about the right age.
うちのいとこも 年齢的にちょうどいいです
How about I send you his pic?
連絡先を教えようか
Handsome, right?
イケメンだろ？
My brother is also quite handsome.
兄貴も結構イケメンなんだ
The guy upstairs from me could do.
うちの上の階の 兄ちゃんもぴったりかも
My cousin will definitely agree. No need to ask.
いとこなら 絶対にオッケーしてくれる
Coach, what's wrong?
コーチ どうしたの？
I saw the messages in the group chat.
グループのメッセージ見たぞ
If it's Saturday,
土曜日なら
I have time.
空いてる
Are you saying
それって
you're willing to take couple photos with me?
撮影パートナーに なってくれるってこと？
As for the specific fee,
具体的な費用は
let's settle it based on the actual situation.
状況に応じて精算しょう
Words cannot express my gratitude.
ありがとう
Come with me.
ついてきて
Where are we going?
どこ行くんだ？
My grandpa's room.
おじいちゃんの部屋よ
Are we looking for something?
何か探すのか
The clothes my grandpa and grandma left behind.
祖父母が残した服よ
That's a vintage photography studio, you know.
レトロな写真館でしょ
I want to wear their clothes
２人の服を着たいの
to make it feel more ceremonial.
そのほうが特別感があるじゃない
-Actually, I have... -You look over there. I'll search this.
- 実は 私は - あなたはあっち 私はこっちを探すね
I haven't found anything yet.
こっちはまだ見つからないの
What about you?
そっちは？
Here...
こっちは
This amusement park
この遊園地は
was the source of my childhood joy.
子供の頃の私の楽しみの源だったの
Grandpa used to take me there all the time.
おじいちゃんが よく連れてきてくれた
Grandpa and I even used to make bets
おじいちゃんと賭けをしたの
on who would get on the carousel first.
どっちが先に メリーゴーラウンドに着くかって
What's this?
これは？
Can you wiggle your ears?
耳 動かせる？
Like this.
こうやって
Impressive, right?
すごいでしょ？
Impressive.
すごい
You try it.
やってみて
Did they wiggle?
動いた？
Formal name Lin Wanxing,
名は林晚星
nickname Shining Star Genius...
あだ名はキラキラお星様天才
Princess.
殿下
You're laughing at me.
笑ったわね？
I'm not laughing.
笑ってない
I could even see your teeth. Still denying it.
歯が見えてるのに笑ってないって
You're still laughing.
ほら まだ笑ってる
I'm not laughing at you, Shining Star Genius Princess.
キラキラお星様天才殿下を 笑ってなんかいない
Let's keep looking.
探し続けよ
Found it.
あった
Isn't this too small for me?
私には小さすぎるだろ
My grandfather was also very tall.
うちのおじいちゃんも 背が高かったから
You can definitely fit into it.
絶対着られるって
Just make do with it.
これで我慢してよ
Felix Yu,
余波
[Felix Yu]
[余波]
I have an honorable task for you:
お前に光栄な任務を与える
go to my house and sneak out a vintage suit for me.
うちからレトロなスーツを 一着拝借してきてくれ
Which house? In Hengjiu?
どの家だ？恒久の方か
Yes.
うん
What's going on? Cosplay?
何だこれ コスプレか
I think I found my grandmother's too.
おばあちゃんのも見つかったみたい
It should be this one.
これのはず
They seem to be a set.
セットみたい
[Felix Yu]
[余波]
Hello, hello, hello?
おいおい
Where are you?
どこだよ？
I don't need your help anymore.
もういい
You may leave.
下がってよし
Ms. Lin.
林先生
How do I look?
どうだ？
A bit less handsome than my grandpa.
おじいちゃんにはかなわないかな
Might as well commit to the act.
やるなら最後までやらないと
[A Snapshot of Time]
[時の垣間]
Hello, Boss.
すみません
We have a 1:30 appointment
１時半に予約した者ですが
for a couples' photo-shoot session.
カップルフォトの撮影です
Hello.
はい こんにちは
Okay.
はい
Let me check.
確認しますね
Mr. Wang and Ms. Lin, right?
王さんと林さんですね
Yes.
はい
Here are some styles for your reference.
こちらに参考のスタイルが
You two can take a look first.
お二人でご覧になってください
-Thank you. -I'll go get ready.
- ありがとうございます - 準備します。
No match.
無いわ
Let's go check over there.
あっちを見てみよう
There are some more up here.
上にもまだあるみたい
Boss, we'll wait for you upstairs.
店主さん 上で待ってます
Help yourselves.
ご自由に
[Golden Wedding Anniversary]
[金婚記念]
[August 23, 2021]
[2021年8月23日]
What's wrong?
どうした？
Found it.
あった
They're my grandparents.
これ 私のおじいちゃんと おばあちゃんなの
Sorry
すみません
to keep you waiting.
お待たせしました
We're all set for the photo-shoot.
撮影を始めます
Let me just adjust the lights.
まず照明を調整します
Boss.
あの
Excuse me, but
お聞きしたいのですが
did you take this photo?
この写真はあなたが 撮ったものですか
I didn't take this.
いえ これは私じゃなくて
My dad took it.
親父が撮ったものです
This is his proudest work.
これが親父の一番の自信作でして
And he shot it with old-fashioned film.
しかも古いフィルムで撮ったんです
See, he even numbered this photo.
写真に番号まで振ってるでしょう
Can you please sell it to me?
これを私に売っていただけませんか
No can do. I'm sorry.
それはできません 申し訳ない
Please, Boss.
お願いします 店主さん
They were my closest family in this world.
２人はこの世で 一番大切な人なんです
And they are long gone.
もうこの世にはいません
I really want to buy it as a keepsake.
どうしても これを買って形見にしたいんです
Please make an exception.
どうかお願いします
I'm sorry.
申し訳ありません
Let's just proceed with the photo-shoot.
撮影を続けましょう
[Golden Wedding Anniversary]
[金婚記念]
Are you guys Xunya and Yuanyuan?
尋涯さんと元元さんかい
You're here to pick up your photos, right?
写真を取りに来たんだろう
Dad.
親父
Why did you come downstairs?
どうして下りてきたんだ？
This is my dad.
うちの親父です
He's a bit...
その…
He thinks it's still 30 years ago.
30年前だと思ってるみたいで
I've been waiting for you.
ずっと待っていたんだよ
You're finally here.
やっと来てくれた
I want to take another picture of you.
もう一度 写真を撮ってあげたいんだ
Get ready, you two.
さあ ２人とも準備して
Come on, get ready.
ほら 準備して
It seems this old gentleman
どうやらこのおじいさんは
-is a friend of my grandparents. -Do you mind letting my dad take the photos?
- 祖父母の友人みたい - 父に写真を撮らせても良いでしょうか？
No problem.
問題ありません
T-Thank you.
ありがとうございます
I'll go get ready.
準備します
Could he be the one who led us here?
この人が私たちを ここに導いたのかしら
Are you alright?
大丈夫か
I'll play along for now.
ひとまず合わせよう
Oh no, it's blurry.
ダメだ ぶれた
Let's try again.
もう１回
Come on, get ready.
さあ 準備して
One, two...
いち にの
What's going on?
どうしたんだ？
It's still blurry.
またピントが合わない
I'm sorry, you two.
お２人とも申し訳ありません
Sorry for wasting your time.
お時間を取らせてしまって
It's fine. We're not in a hurry.
大丈夫です 急いでないので
Let's try again.
もう１回
How about I do it, Dad?
俺がやるよ 親父
Go away.
あっち行け
Use the tripod. Here.
三脚だ ほら
Xunya.
尋涯さん
Did you two have a fight?
夫婦でケンカでもしたのか
-We didn't.
- してません
Then show me some chemistry.
なら もっと雰囲気を出して
Chemistry?
雰囲気？
Chemistry.
雰囲気だ
He probably means
つまり
♪ I caught your eyes ♪
♪ 君のまなざしを見つけた ♪
a little physical contact
もう少し体を寄せ合って
♪ On the summer night ♪
♪ あの夏の夜に ♪
and a brighter smile.
満面の笑みでってこと
♪ A star that glows so bright ♪
♪ 眩しく輝く星のようだった ♪
This is good.
そう そう
Come on.
いいね
Much better. Let's take another one.
ずっといいね もう１枚
♪ A spark in my heart ♪
♪ 胸に灯る小さな火は ♪
Be closer.
もっと近づいて
♪ Disappear in my dream, secretly ♪
♪ 夢の中へ そっと消えてゆく ♪
Ms. Lin, put your hand on my shoulder.
林先生 手を私の肩に置いて
♪ With the evening breeze whispering in my ear ♪
♪ 夜風が耳元に 吹き寄せる告白 ♪
Look at me.
私を見て
♪ Fireworks bloom across the sky ♪
♪ 空いっぱいの花火が 咲き誇る ♪
♪ Shimmering in your eyes ♪
♪ あなたの瞳に映り込んで ♪
♪ And spreading into a gentle sea of stars ♪
♪ やさしさとなって広がる 星の海 ♪
♪ Every night ♪
♪ 毎晩 ♪
Good.
いいぞ
This one is good.
これはいい
♪ I reach for starlight ♪
♪ 星の光に 手を伸ばす ♪
♪ Wandering through dreams with you ♪
♪ 君と夢の中を彷徨う ♪
♪ I follow the beat of my heart ♪
♪ 鼓動のリズムに乗せて ♪
♪ Like dust floating in the air ♪
♪ 宙を舞う塵のように ♪
♪ Because of your love ♪
♪ 君の愛が ♪
♪ I shine brilliantly ♪
♪ 私を輝かせる ♪
Isn't the size a bit too big?
これ ちょっとやり過ぎじゃない？
It's well taken.
よく撮れてる
We absolutely cannot let those kids see this.
あの子たちにだけは 絶対見せられない
Are the photos ready?
写真はできたかな
This bracelet is...
この腕輪は...
You are...
あなたは
Y-You're not Yuanyuan.
いや 元元さんじゃないな
Who are you?
どなたかね？
Yuanyuan was my grandmother.
元元は私の祖母です
My name is Lin Wanxing.
私は林晚星と申します
I'm the granddaughter of Lin Xunya and Shen Shuyuan.
林尋涯と沈淑元の孫です
Right.
そうだ
I just remembered
思い出した
something very important.
大事な用事が一つ
[9 months ago]
[９ヶ月前]
Hello. Hello?
すみません
Excuse me,
あの
are you the owner of this shop?
店主でしょうか
Are you here for a photo-shoot?
写真かい？
I'm here to collect a photo.
取りに来ました
Come on in.
入りな
Lin Xunya.
林尋涯
Who are you?
どなたかね？
Why didn't Xunya come pick it up himself?
尋涯さんはなぜ 自分で取りに来ないんだ
[Receipt]
[レシート]
Shortly after this photo was taken,
林旦那はこの写真を撮ったあと
Mr. Lin was diagnosed with cancer.
がんと診断され
He passed away not long ago.
先日 亡くなりました
What about his wife, Shen Shuyuan?
では奥さんの沈淑元さんは？
Mrs. Shen also passed away
沈奥様は林旦那が 亡くなって間もなく
not long after Mr. Lin did.
後を追うように亡くなりました
I see.
そうだったのか
[Lin Xunya and Shen Shuyuan's Golden Wedding Anniversary]
[林尋涯と沈淑元の金婚記念]
I really like this photo,
この写真がすごく気に入ってね
so I enlarged it
だから引き伸ばして
and kept it hanging upstairs.
ずっと２階に飾ってたんだ
I was planning to take another photo for them
写真を取りに来たら
when they came to pick this one up.
もう１枚撮ってあげようと 思ってたんだが
Who would have thought...
まさかな
At least
少なくとも
they're together again now.
２人はまた一緒になれました
Oh, by the way.
そうだ
I have one more small request.
実は１つお願いがあるのですが
I hope you can do me this favor.
お聞き届けいただけないでしょうか
Since you know Xunya,
尋涯さんと知り合いなら
that makes you sort of a friend of mine.
私の友達みたいなもんだ
Go ahead.
言ってみな
Open it and take a look.
開けてみてくれ
I also have no idea
なぜこれを私にくれたか
why he entrusted these things to me.
私も分からん
He said
その人は
that one day, Xunya's descendants
将来 尋涯の子孫が
would come to collect them.
取りに来ると
So I just accepted them in a daze.
訳も分からず預かったんだ
Sir,
おじいさん
do you remember his name?
その人の名前を覚えてますか
I don't think he left a name.
名前は聞いてないようだ
[No. 7, Wutong Road]
[梧桐路７号]
♪ Waiting for a dark cloud to pass by you ♪
♪ 一つの雲が 君を過ぎる ♪
♪ Listen closely to its cries ♪
♪ その泣き声を 聴いて ♪
♪ The heavy rain will wash away your reflection ♪
♪ 大雨が 君の面影を さらう ♪
♪ And carry it toward distant scenery ♪
♪ 遠くの 景色へ ♪
[No. 7, Wutong Road]
[梧桐路07]
♪ Every experience has its meaning ♪
♪ すべての経験に 意味がある ♪
Give it to me.
私にくれ
♪ Scene by scene, they come together to form who I am ♪
♪ 一つ一つが 自分になる ♪
♪ Even the wounds that leave behind their marks ♪
♪ 傷跡さえも 残しても ♪
♪ Have taught me how to heal myself ♪
♪ 癒やし方も 教えてくれた ♪
♪ The love I have given, the love I have received ♪
♪ 与えた愛も 持ってる愛も ♪
Grandpa!
おじいちゃん
What brings you here, Wanxing?
どうしたの？星ちゃん
I have something to tell you.
あのね
I saw a really big tadpole
学校でね
♪ Every one of them gives me the strength not to fear being hurt ♪
♪ 一つ一つが 私を 強くする ♪
at school,
大きいおたまじゃくしを見つけたの
and I want to bring it home and raise it into a frog.
カエルになるまで育てたい
Okay. Go find Grandma.
いいとも おばあちゃんの所へ 行きなさい
♪ Let my tears be carried away, back into the ocean ♪
♪ 涙をさらい 海へ還る ♪
I'm in the middle of a class.
おじいちゃんは授業があるから
Be good.
おじいちゃんは授業よ
Let's go to the yard.
お庭に行こう
Alright, where were we?
さて どこまで話したかな
Here, "hold the line."
ここだ 「固守」
-And this. -Don't make a sound.
- これは... - 音を立てないでね
♪ And blown toward flowers blooming far away ♪
♪ 遠くの 花へ吹く ♪
Let's go draw over there.
あっちでお絵描きしようか
Come on.
おいで
Here, give me the bag.
ほら カバンを貸して
♪ I fill the blank spaces of life with colors ♪
♪ 命の余白を 彩ってゆく ♪
Come on, sit here.
ここに座って
Okay, Grandma.
うん おばあちゃん
Grandma, time to draw.
おばあちゃん お絵描きする
What do you want to draw?
何を描くの？
♪ My dreams are not afraid to awaken; they continue to exist ♪
♪ 私の夢は 覚めても 消えない ♪
♪ I go beyond the dark clouds and feel the haze disperse ♪
♪ 雲の向こう 晴れ渡る ♪
♪ Let me understand myself more clearly ♪
♪ 自分がもっと 見えてくる ♪
Bye.
さようなら
Grandpa!
おじいちゃん
Look what I drew.
見て 私が描いたの
You drew so well.
上手だね
What is it that you drew?
これは何を描いたんだい？
This is Grandpa,
これがおじいちゃんで
this is me,
これが私
and this is Grandma.
これがおばあちゃんよ
You drew so well.
本当に上手だ
♪ Every experience has its meaning ♪
♪ すべての経験に 意味がある ♪
You won't be able to draw this when you grow up.
大人でも描けない絵だ
Grandpa, your watch is so pretty.
おじいちゃんの腕時計 すごくきれい
♪ Scene by scene, they come together to form who I am ♪
♪ 一つ一つが 自分になる ♪
I want it too.
私も欲しいな
This was a gift
これはおばあちゃんが
from Grandma.
おじいちゃんに贈った プレゼントなんだ
♪ Even the wounds that leave behind their marks ♪
♪ 傷跡さえも 残しても ♪
This was given to me by your Grandma
おじいちゃんが先生になった初日に
on my first day as a teacher.
おばあちゃんが贈ってくれた
How can I just give it to you?
欲しがっちゃダメだよ
Grandma's being unfair.
おばあちゃんのえこひいき
♪ Have taught me how to heal myself ♪
♪ 癒やし方も 教えてくれた ♪
You're still too young.
あなたはまだ小さいから
How about I buy you
おばあちゃんがね
a cartoon watch first, okay?
まずはキャラクターの時計を 買ってあげる
I want Grandpa's.
おじいちゃんのがいいの
♪ I fill the blank spaces of life with colors ♪
♪ 命の余白を 彩ってゆく ♪
Alright, alright.
分かった
Once I retire from Yuanyuan Tutoring Center,
おじいちゃんが元元塾を引退したら
I'll give you this watch.
この時計をあげるよ
Pinky swear.
指切りげんまん
♪ My dreams are not afraid to awaken; they continue to exist ♪
♪ 私の夢は 覚めても 消えない ♪
Okay.
うん
Pinky swear.
指切りした
What does Yuanyuan mean?
元元ってどういう意味？
[Yuanyuan Tutoring Center]
[元元塾]
Yuanyuan.
元元
Yuanyuan is Grandma's nickname.
元元はおばあちゃんのあだ名だよ
♪ I go beyond the dark clouds and feel the haze disperse ♪
♪ 雲の向こう 晴れ渡る ♪
Her parents gave her this nickname
おばあちゃんの お父さんとお母さんが
with a special meaning.
このあだ名をつけたのは
"Yuanyuan" was meant to remind her to study diligently.
しっかり勉強しなさい という意味でね
♪ Let me understand myself more clearly ♪
♪ 自分がもっと 見えてくる ♪
“Yuanyuan" comes from "the countless living beings."
元元とは すなわち芸芸衆生
[Yuanyuan Tutoring Center]
[元元塾]
The purpose of studying is to care for
学問を志すのは
and serve all living beings.
世の全ての人々を思うためだ
♪ Take away my reflection ♪
♪ 私の 面影を さらう ♪
Yuanyuan Tutoring Center?
元元塾
Yuanyuan
元元
♪ And go in search of distant scenery ♪
♪ 遠くの 景色へ ♪
was my grandma's name.
祖母の名前なの
My grandpa was a Chinese teacher,
おじいちゃんは国語の教師で
and my grandma was an art teacher.
おばあさんは美術教師だったの
They taught for a lifetime,
２人は生涯 教師だった
and didn't stop after retiring.
退職後も休むことなく
This watch used to belong to my grandpa.
これはおじいちゃんの腕時計よ
He promised
彼は言ってた
that once I grew up,
私が大人になったら
he'd give it to me.
これをくれると
Your grandpa took really good care of it.
おじいさんは大切に 保管してたんだな
It looks brand new.
新品みたいだ
Once I retire from Yuanyuan Tutoring Center,
おじいちゃんが元元塾を引退したら
I'll give this watch to you.
この時計はあげるよ
Pinky swear.
指切りげんまん
Okay.
うん
[Yuanyuan Tutoring Center]
[元元塾]
“Yuanyuan" comes from "the countless living beings."
元元とは すなわち芸芸衆生
The purpose of studying
学問を志すのは
is to care for and serve all living beings.
世の全ての人々を思うためだ
I've made up my mind.
決めたの
I will stay here
私はここで
and tutor those kids.
あの子たちの補習を手伝う
For all living beings,
芸芸衆生
for the fruits of hard work—
累々たる秋の実
what Grandpa and Grandma devoted their lives to doing,
おじいちゃんと おばあちゃんがしてたこと
I'll carry it on for them.
私が代わりに続けていく
Grandpa.
おじいちゃん
I think I finally understand
どうして私を 宏景八高に行かせたのか
why you sent me to Hongjing No. 8 High School.
やっと分かった気がする
Don't worry.
安心して
From now on,
これからは
I'll never give up on myself again because of anyone.
もう誰のためにも 自分を見捨てたりしない
Over this past month or so,
この１か月あまり
I've been really happy.
すごく楽しかった
Thank you for your gift, Grandpa.
星へのプレゼント ありがとう おじいちゃん
Grandpa,
おじいちゃん
Grandma,
おばあちゃん
I miss you so much.
会いたいよ
Although I don't know who the mysterious person is
謎の人物が誰か分からないし
or where he wants to lead us,
私たちをどこに 導きたいのかも分からない
I can feel his kindness and help.
でも 彼の善意と助けは感じられる
Maybe if we let nature take its course,
きっと自然に任せていれば
we'll eventually find out who he really is someday.
いつか彼の正体が分かる日が来るわ
Which number was it again?
何番だっけ？
-No. 7, I think. -No. 7.
- ７番だろ -７番
-Where is No. 7?
７番はどこだ？
-This is No. 6. -That one.
- これは６番
-This is No. 7. -This is No. 5.
- ７番はここだ - これは５番だ
Here it is. Over here.
ここだ ここ
No. 7 is here.
７番はここだ
It's so big.
こんなに大きいのか
-Do you think it's Ms. Lin's house? -This is No. 7?
- ここは林先生の家なのか - これは７番地だ
That's very likely.
あり得る
Such a big house.
こんなに大きいなんて
Why is it so run-down inside?
中は随分と荒れてるけど
It's too heavy. Put it down for now.
重すぎる 一旦置いて
-It's run-down. -Hello? Anyone in there?
- 放棄されているのか - 誰か？
H-How could this be?
まさか そんなはずは...
There are people here.
ここよ
-Ms. Lin.
- 林先生
Coach.
コーチ
It was Coach who asked us to come.
コーチに呼ばれたんだろ？
Ms. Lin, why are you here too?
林先生も どうしてここに？
Because this is the place where
ここは
you'll be having your tutoring sessions.
あなたたちの補習場所であり
It's also our team's secret base.
私たちのチームの 秘密基地でもあるの
Secret base?
秘密基地？
This whole building? We have such a big place to ourselves?
この建物全部が 俺たちの場所に
You see this?
見たか
This is pretty cool.
ちょっとカッコいいな
It's this clean?
こんなにきれいなのか
This is the room.
この部屋に入ればすぐよ
It's a classroom.
教室か
Even the door's broken.
ドアまで壊れてる
Yuanyuan Tutoring Center?
元元塾
So
なるほど
our secret base is called Yuanyuan Tutoring Center.
俺たちの秘密基地は 元元塾って名前か
How much longer do you think it'll take us to finish cleaning today?
今日 あとどれくらい 掃除するんだ？
At least 3 or 4 hours.
どう見ても３ ４時間はかかる
Boss, are you wearing a watch?
兄貴 時計は？
Zheng is. What time is it?
鄭が持ってる 何時だ？
Yeah, check what time it is.
そうだ 今何時だ？
Clean it properly.
きれいに掃除しろよ
Just do your own work.
自分の仕事しろ
You talk too much.
しゃべってばかり
There are so many people here.
まだこんなに人が...
-Fu, you're here. -Yes.
- 付が来た -来たか
Come on, Fu.
さあ 付
Mop the outside first.
先に外を拭け
I'll help you first,
先に手伝うから
then you help me.
後で手伝って
You guys be careful.
そっちも気をつけろよ
Ms. Lin.
林先生
If I'm not mistaken,
私の計算が正しければ
you've been wiping this marble counter
その大理石のテーブルを
for 20 minutes.
もう20分も拭いてるぞ
I said we'd come clean this morning,
朝から大掃除とは言ったけど
but I never meant this early.
こんなに早いなんて聞いてない
I'm out of energy.
エネルギー切れよ
About to crash.
システムダウン寸前
An hour in the morning is worth two in the evening.
一日の計は朝にあり
An hour in the morning is something I simply can't afford.
早起きは無理よ
You can still joke around.
まだふざける元気があるのか
It seems you're not really out of energy.
なら まだ大丈夫そうだな
I've got a mission for you.
君にミッションを与えよう
See that recliner over there?
あそこの寝椅子 見えるか
I just cleaned it.
私が洗っておいた
Go lie down there.
あそこで横になって
Whenever a mop comes by, lift your legs up.
モップが来たら足を上げるんだ
Think you can handle it?
できるか
Thank you.
ありがとう
-Mop. -Where's the mop?
- ふきん - ふきんはどこだ？
Right here.
ここ ここ
Why is it so dirty?
なんでこんなに汚いんだ？
Why is it so big?
広すぎ
It's too big, bro.
広すぎるだろ
There's a balcony here.
ベランダがあるぞ
How long will it take for us to clean?
いつまで掃除すりゃいいんだ？
Guys!
みんな
There's another huge balcony up here!
この上にすごく広いベランダがある
-Let's go take a look. -Let's go.
行こうぜ 見に行こう
The view is so nice.
景色がいいな
We'll be having classes here from now on.
これからはここで授業をするのか
Yeah.
そうだな
-This feels so great. -We'll be having classes here.
- やったぞ - これからはここで授業だ
Let's start sweeping from the bottom and work our way up.
じゃあ 下から上を掃除しようか
-Sure. -Let's go.
-ああ - 行こう！
♪ Night slips through my fingers ♪
♪ 夜が 指の隙間を抜ける ♪
♪ Embracing the coldness of wakefulness ♪
♪ 冴えた冷たさを 抱く ♪
♪ Whispering my thoughts alone ♪
♪ ひとり 心をつぶやく ♪
♪ Saying goodbye to the evening breeze we met by chance ♪
♪ 偶然の夜風に 別れを ♪
♪ Staying with the jasmine blossoms until late spring ♪
♪ ジャスミンと 暮春まで ♪
♪ Watching their elegance fade, their fragrance disappear ♪
♪ 香りは 静かに薄れる ♪
♪ I once dreamed of beauty ♪
♪ 美しさを 夢見た ♪
♪ And I accept that regrets may grow wild ♪
♪ 悔いが募ることも 受け入れる ♪
♪ Look, beneath the sunlight ♪
♪ 陽だまりを 見つめて ♪
♪ In the dancing specks of dust ♪
♪ 舞う塵の中で ♪
♪ I'm grateful I never lost my sincerity ♪
♪ 真剣さを 失わずに ♪
♪ Or my gift for happiness ♪
♪ 幸せの 才能 ♪
♪ Sharing my warmth with a passing rain ♪
♪ 雨と ぬくもりを分け合う ♪
♪ Quietly feeling its journey ♪
♪ 静かに その旅を感じる ♪
♪ Like a firefly vanishing in an instant ♪
♪ 蛍火のように 儚く ♪
♪ Still beautiful in its entirety ♪
♪ それでも 美しいまま ♪
♪ There's no need to seek a final answer ♪
♪ 答えを 求めなくていい ♪
♪ Let the ending remain with questions unanswered ♪
♪ 終わりに 迷いを残して ♪
♪ No need to prove it with promises ♪
♪ 誓いに 頼らなくていい ♪
♪ The dusk when we once vowed to stay together ♪
♪ 共にいると 誓った夕暮れ ♪
♪ No need to cling to forever ♪
♪ 永遠に こだわらず ♪
♪ Allow separation to happen ♪
♪ 別れを 許そう ♪